Matt Bass UX Designer & Researcher

Entertainment storyteller turned experience designer, user advocate & problem solver. I combine research and testing to deliver experiences so intuitive to users they feel invisible. Front end skills for easier developer handoff.

(424) 254-9108 matt@mattbass.design www.mattbass.design

EXPERIENCE

Matt Bass Design — Freelance Designer

2018 - PRESENT

User centric mobile and desktop designer pairing user needs with business goals.. Taking user research and testing to inform user stories, mockups and wireframes.

Recent Projects

Access America - Lead Designer

(in progress)

Pro bono, open source project for Humanity Forward, creating a new and secure digital program for citizens to interact with the government.

SMITH EMERY — **Designer**

(in progress)

Redesign of company brochure, improving page count and legibility with new design system. Redesign of website for auxiliary brand.

CINEMA MAKEUP SCHOOL – **Primary UX Designer**

(Six weeks)

Redesign, using existing SEO data for a research driven outcome. Improved accessibility with bottom pinned mobile menu. Increased legibility and clarity through typography, visual system structure and UX content. Upgraded UI design.

DESIGN READS – UX Research & Design Team Member

(3 Months)

iOS SaaS app to share UX resources. Remote designer collaboration, organized by kanban board. Organized IA with user research, and translating results into wireframes. Created UX content.

VILLAGE - Primary UX Designer

(1 month sprint)

iOS Saas app improving school communication. Researched market and potential users to uncover MVP needs. Resulting data informed creation of stories, flows & site maps, wireframes, and UI elements. Multiple round user testing with prototypes to refine decisions. Created visual design, branding & style guide.

Chemical Imbalance Management — Literary Manager & Producer

2011 - PRESENT

Strategic literary representation, helping screenwriter clients develop ideas then partnering with talent. Sold a range of film/tv projects as a producer.

HBO — Film Development Executive

2001 - 2010

Acquired/developed material to expand brand. Partnered with other departments to source new projects and talent relationships.

UX SKILL SET

Branding Information Architecture Strategic Analysis User Research & Testing UX Writing

UI TOOLS

Adobe

Axure RP

Draw.io

Figma

Invision

Sketch

Zeplin

FRONT END SKILLS

HTML & CSS Javascript & JQuery Git & Github

EDUCATION

Bloc.io

UX/UI Design Certification

University Of Southern California

BA - Cinema Television Critical Studies